<resources>

    <string name="app_name">RUET Syllabus</string>

    <string-array name="semesters">
        <item>1st Year odd semester</item>
        <item>1st Year even semester</item>
        <item>2nd Year odd semester</item>
        <item>2nd Year even semester</item>
        <item>3rd Year odd semester</item>
        <item>3rd Year even semester</item>
        <item>4th Year odd semester</item>
        <item>4th Year even semester</item>
    </string-array>

    <string name="about">
        <u><b>Developed By:</b></u>\n
        Alifa Shanzidah Manarat,\n
        CSE 19, RUET.\n\n
         <u><b>Submitted To:</b></u>\n
        Suhrid Shakhar Ghosh,\n
        Assistant Professor,\n
        Dept. of CSE, RUET.\n\n
    </string>

    <string name="contact">
        For any kind of information, \n please reach me at <b>alifa.manarat@gmail.com</b>.\n
    </string>

    <string name="cse_1100">
        <b>Computer Fundamentals:</b> Introduction to Computer Basics, Types and Generation of Computers; Basic Organization and Functional Units.\n
\n<b>Hardware:</b> Basic Units of Computer Hardware; Processors; Input, Output and Memory
Devices; Keyboard; Mouse; OMR; OCR; MICR; CD-ROM; Printers; CRT; LCD; LED;
Microfilm; Floppy.\n\n<b>Software:</b> Types of Software; System Software: Familiarization with Various Operating
Systems (Windows, DOS, UNIX, Android, IOS Etc.); \n\n<b>Application Software:</b> Text
Processing (MS-WORD, etc); Spread Sheet (MS-EXCEL etc).\n\n
<b>Language:</b> Machine Language; Assembly Language; High Level Language; Assembler;
Translator; Interpreter and Compiler.\n\n
<b>Database Management:</b> Introduction of Data, Information and Management; Studying
Various Tools like Foxpro, MS Access, Oracle etc; Mathematical and Simulation (Math
Cad, Matlab etc.); Data Communications and Internet.\n\n
<b>Computer Ethics:</b> Computers in the Workplace; Computer Crime; Rules of
Communications; Privacy; Intellectual Property; Impact on Employment; Professional
Responsibility; Globalization.\n\n
    </string>

    <string name="cse_1101">
        <b>Introduction to Computer Programming:</b> Algorithm, Writing, Debugging and Running
Programs using C/C++ Compiler. \n\n
C/C++ Basics: Different Data Types and their Range, Operator and Operands and its
Precedence, Input/Output, Conditional Operators, Loops Nested Structure, Error
Handling, Built-in Functions\n\n
       <b> Functions and Arrays:</b> Writing and Calling of User–defined Functions, Recursive
Functions, Scope of Variables, Introduction to One-Dimensional Arrays, Multi-Dimensional
Arrays and Array Manipulation.\n\n
<b>Pointers and Strings:</b> Introduction to Pointers, Pointers and Array, Pointers and
Functions, String I/O, String-based Built-in Functions, String Operations, Pointer and
String.\n\n
<b>Files:</b> Introduction to Files in C/C++, Opening, Closing and Updating Binary and
Sequential Files.\n\n
<b>Advanced Topics:</b> Operations on Bits, Register Variable, Pre-Processors and Graphics
in C/C++.\n\n

    </string>

    <string name="eee_1151">
       <b>Basics of Electrical Circuit:</b> Electrical Units and Standards. Electrical Circuit Elements
and Models. Signal and Waveforms. Fourier Representation of Non-Sinusoidal
Waveforms. RMS and Average Value of Sinusoidal Waveforms. Introduction to Phasor
Algebra. DC and Steady State AC Circuit Solutions: Series, Parallel, Series-Parallel
Networks, Loop and Nodal Methods, Delta-Wye Transformations.\n\n
<b>Circuit Theorems:</b> KVL, KCL, Thevenin, Norton, Super-position, Reciprocity and
Maximum Power Transfer Theorems, Resonance. Circuit Analysis using Popular
Simulation Tools\n\n
    </string>

    <string name="math_1113">
        <b>Differential Calculus:</b> Limit, Continuity and Differentiability. Differentiation of Explicit and
Implicit Function and Parametric Equations. Significance of Derivatives, Differentials,
Successive Differentiation of Various Types of Functions. Leibnitzs Theorem. Rolles
Theorem, Mean Value Theorems. Taylors Theorem in Finite and Infinite Forms.
Maclaurins Theorem in Finite and Infinite Forms. Langranges Form of Remainders.
Cauehys Form of Remainder. Expansion of Functions by Differentiation and Integration.
Partial Differentiation. Eulers Theorem. Tangent and Normal, Maxima and Minima, Points
of Inflection and Their Applications. Evaluation of Indeterminate Forms by LHospitals
Rule, Curvature, Evaluate and Inviolate. Asymptotes. Envelopes, Curve Tracing.\n\n
<b>Integral Calculus:</b> Definitions of Integration, Integration by The Method of Substitutions,
Integration by The Method of Successive Reduction. Definite Integrals. Beta Function and
Gamma Function. Area Under a Plane Curve in Cartesian and Polar Co-Ordinates. Area
of the Region Enclosed by Two Curves in Cartesian and Polar Co-Ordinates, Parametric
and Pedal Equations. Intrinsic Equation. Volumes of Solids of Revolution. Volume of
Hollow Solids of Revolution by Shell Method. Area of Surface of Revolution.\n\n
    </string>

    <string name="hum_1113">
        <b>Grammar:</b> Construction and Transformation of Sentences, Analysis of Sentence,
Structure, Use of Preposition, Question Words, WH and Yes/No Question, Phrases and
Idioms, Correction, Conditional Sentences, Punctuation, Pronunciation, Phonetic
Transcription, Spoken English.\n\n
<b>Composition:</b> Definition of Scientific Terms, Comprehension, Precis Writing, Commercial
Correspondence, Paragraph Writing, Amplification, Tenders and Schedules, Memos and
Press-Release, Report Writing.\n\n
        <b>Short Stories:</b>\n
The Diamond Necklace – Guy De Mapausant\n
Meeting in the Mosque – E. M. Forster\n
Tickets, Please – D. H. Lawrence\n
The Dead – James Joyce\n\n
    </string>

    <string name="hum_1114">
        <b>Developing Reading Skill:</b> Strategies of Reading Skimming, Scanning, Predicting,
Inferencing, Practicing Comprehension from Literary and Non Literary Texts.\n\n
        <b>Developing Writing Skill:</b> Sentence Variety; Generating Sentences, Clarity and
Correctness of Sentences, Linking Sentences for Paragraphs, Writing Paragraphs,
Essays, Reports Formal and Informal Letters.\n\n
<b>Developing Listening Skill:</b> Listening to Recorded Texts and Class Lectures and
Learning to Take Notes.\n\n
    </string>

    <string name="chem_1113">
        <b>Chemical Bond:</b> Different Types of Chemical Bonds; Properties of Ionic and Covalent
Compounds, Modern Approach of Covalent Bond.\n\n
<b>Thermo-chemistry:</b> Types of Energy, Enthalpy of Reaction, Heat of Combustion, Heat of
Formation and Heat of Neutralization, Experimental Determination of Thermal Changes
During Chemical Reaction.\n\n
<b>Titration:</b> Acid Base Titration and its Problem During the Process of Titration.\n\n
<b>Solution:</b> Types of Solution, Factors Influencing the Solubility of Substance. Mechanism of
Dissolution; Solution of Gases in Liquids, Different Units of Concentration, Distribution Law
and its Application; Properties of Dilute Solution, Raoults Law - its Application, Elevation of
Boiling Point, Depression of Freezing Point and Osmotic Pressure.\n\n
<b>Electro-chemistry:</b> Electrolytes, Mechanism of Electrolytic Conduction, Transport Number
and Electrolytic Conductance.\n\n
<b>Kinetics and Chemical Equilibrium:</b> Rate of a Reaction, Factors Determining the Rate,
Law of Mass Action, Evaluation and Characteristics of Equilibrium Constant of Reaction;
the Lechatcliers Principle.\n\n
<b>Colloid:</b> Colloids and Properties of Colloidal System and its Application. \n\n
    </string>

    <string name="cse_1200">
        Student will Solve at least 30 (Thirty) Problems using C, C++ or Java. Among them at
Least three Problems should be Submitted from Geometry, Mathematics, String
Processing, Tree, Graph and Sorting Techniques.\n\n
    </string>

    <string name="cse_1201">
        <b>Introduction:</b> Concepts and Examples of Elementary Data Objects, Necessity of
Structured Data, Types of Data Structure, Ideas on Linear and Nonlinear Data Structure.\n\n
<b>Linear Array:</b> Linear Array and its Representation in Memory, Traversing LA, Insertion and
Deletion in LA, Bubble Sort, Linear Search and Binary Search, Multidimensional Array and its
Representation in Memory, Algebra of Matrices, Sparse Matrices.\n\n
<b>Stack:</b> Stack Representation and Applications; PUSH and POP Operation on Stack. Polish
Notation, Reverse Polish Notation; Evaluation of a Postfix Expression; Transforming
Infix Expression into Postfix Expression.\n\n
<b>Queue:</b> Its Representation, Insertion and Deletion in Queue, Priority Queues, Recursion
[Factorial Function, Fibonacci Sequence, Ackermann Function, Towers of Hanoi].\n\n
<b>Linked List:</b> Linked List and its Representation in Memory, Traversing, Searching, Insertion
and Deletion Operation on Linked List, Circular List, Header Linked Lists, Two Way Lists.\n\n
<b>Complexity:</b> Algorithm and Flow Chart, Complexity of Algorithms, Rate of Growth, Big O
Notation, Complexity of Linear Search, Binary Search and Bubble Sort Algorithm. \n\n
<b>Sorting:</b> Insertion Sort, Selection Sort, Quick Sort, Merge Sort, Searching and Data
Modification, Hash Function, Collision Resolution, Chaining.\n\n
<b>Tree:</b> Tree Terminology, Representation of Binary Trees in Memory, Traversing Binary
Tree, Binary Search Tree, Insertion and Deletion on Binary Search Tree, Insertion and
Deletion on Heap, Heap Sort, B Trees, General Tree.\n\n
    </string>

    <string name="cse_1203">
        <b>Fundamentals of OOP:</b> Introduction to Object Oriented Programming, Principles of
Object Oriented Design, Encapsulation and Information-hiding, Inheritance,
Polymorphism, Data Binding, Static and Dynamic Binding.\n\n
<b>Classes and Objects:</b> Structure of Class, Access Modifiers, Nested Classes, Abstract
Classes, Arrays of Objects, Pointer to Objects, Friend function, Data abstraction.\n\n
<b>Constructors and Destructors:</b> Default Constructor, Copy Constructor, Dynamic
Constructor, Constructor Function for Derived Class and their Order of Execution,
Destructor.\n\n
<b>Inheritance:</b> Single Inheritance vs. Multiple Inheritance, Mode of Inheritance, Virtual
Inheritance. \n\n
<b>Polymorphism:</b> Operator and Function Overloading, Run-Time and Compile Time
Polymorphism, Virtual Function, Errors and Exception Handling.\n\n
<b>Advanced Topics:</b> Persistent Objects, Objects and Portable Data, UML Basics, Design
Patterns, Multithreading.\n\n
<b>Reference Programming Language(s):</b> C++ and Java.\n\n
    </string>

    <string name="math_1213">
        <b>Co-ordinate Geometry:</b> Co-ordinate Geometry of Two Dimensions: Change of Axes,
Transformation of Co-Ordinates, Simplification of Equations of Curves.\n\n
<b>Co-ordinate Geometry of Three Dimensions:</b> System of Co-Ordinates, Distance
between two Points, Section Formula, Direction Cosines and Projection, Planes and
Straight Lines.\n\n
<b>Ordinary Differential Equation:</b> Degree and Order of Ordinary Differential Equations.
Formation of Differential Equations. Solutions of First Order Differential Equations by
Various Methods, Solutions of General Linear Differential Equations of Second and
Higher Orders with Constant Coefficients, Solution of Homogeneous Linear Differential
Equations. Solution of Higher Order Differential Equations when the Dependent of
Independent Variables are Absent. Solution of Differential Equation with Constant
Coefficients by Operator Method. Differential Equations with Variable Coefficients.\n\n
    </string>

    <string name="hum_1213">
        <b>Economics:</b> Nature of the Economics Theory Applicability of Economic Theory to the
Problems of Developing Countries, Some Basic Concepts Supply, Demand and their
Elasticity. Economics and Technology. Producers Equilibrium-Isoquant. Production -
Factors of Production, Production Possibility Curve-Equilibrium of a Firm, Fixed Cost and
Variable Cost, Laws of Returns ,Internal and External Economics and Dis-Economics,
Input Output Analysis. Economic Growth and Economic Development and Planning Basic
Concept-Saving, Investment, GNP, NNP, Per-Capita Income, Growth Rate, Fiscal Policy,
Monetary Policy and Trade Policy and their Relative Applicability in Bangladesh, Planning-Five Year Plans of Bangladesh, Development Problems Related to Agriculture. Industry
and Population of Bangladesh.\n\n
<b>Government:</b> Basic Concepts of Government and Politics. Functions, Organs and Forms
of Modern State and Government, Socialism. Capitalism, UNO, Government and Politics
of Bangladesh, Some Major Administrative Systems of Developed Counties. Local Self -
Government. Central Government, Public Opinion.\n\n
<b>Sociology:</b> Scope, Culture and Civilization Relationship, Social Structure of Bangladesh.
Industrial Revolution, Urbanization and Industrialization, Urban Ecology, Cyber Crime and
Delinquency, Sociology of Education. Relationship-Sociology and Cyber Crime. Causes
and Remedies of Cyber Crime.\n\n
    </string>

    <string name="phy_1213">
        <b>Structure of Matter:</b> Structure of Matter. Different Types of Bonds in Solids: Metallic, Van
Dar Waals‟, Covalent and Ionic Bond, Packing in Solids: Inter Atomic Distances and
Forces of Equilibrium, X-Ray Diffraction, Bragg‟s Law. Distinction Insulator,
Semiconductor and Conductor.\n\n
<b>Atomic Physics:</b> Atom Models: Thomson Atom Model, Rutherford Atom Model,
Rutherford Scattering Formula, Electron Orbits, Bohr Atom Model, Energy Levels and
Spectra, Particle Properties of Waves: Photoelectric Effect, Einstein‟s Photoelectric
Equation, Laws of Photoelectric Emission, Photovoltaic Cells, Compton Effect. Wave
Properties of Particle: De Broglie Waves, Group Velocity, Phase Velocity.\n\n
<b>Waves and Oscillations:</b> Oscillations: Simple Harmonic Motion, Composition of Simple
Harmonic Motions and Lissajous‟ Figures, Damped and Forced Oscillations. Resonance.
Waves: Travelling and Standing Waves, Energy Calculation of Traveling and Standing
Waves, Intensity of Waves. Beats, Doppler Effect.\n\n
<b>Theories of Light:</b> Wave Theory: Huygens Wave Theory. Huygens Principle and
Construction, Superposition of Light Waves. Electromagnetic Theory. Particle Theory:
Newton‟s Corpuscular Theory, Quantum Theory of Light.\n\n
Interference: Introduction, Conditions of Interference, Young‟s Double Slit Experiment,
Fresnels Biprism. Thin Film Interference, Interference Due to Multiple Reflection, Newtons
Ring.\n\n
<b>Diffraction:</b> Fresnel‟s and Fraunhoper Diffraction, Diffraction by Single and Double Slit,
Diffraction Gratings.\n\n
<b>Polarization:</b> Introduction, Methods of Producing Polarized Light, Polarization by
Reflection and Refraction, Polarization by Double Refraction, Constrauvtion of Nicol
Prism, Production and Analysis of Polarized Light, Optical Activity, Optics of Crystals,
Polarimeters.\n\n
    </string>

    <string name="cse_2101">
        <b>Set:</b> Operations on Sets, Algebraic Properties of Set, Computer Representation of Set,
Cantors Diagonal Argument and the Power Set Theorem, Schroeder-Bernstein Theorem.\n\n
<b>Relation:</b> Property of Relation, Binary Relations, Partial Ordering Relations, Equivalence
Relations.\n\n
<b>Function:</b> Type of Functions, Growth of Function.\n
Propositional Logic: Syntax, Semantics, Valid, Satisfiable and Unsatisfiable Formulas,
Encoding and Examining the Validity of Some Logical Arguments, Predicate and
Quantifier, Universal and Existential Quantification; Modus Ponens and Modus Tollens.\n\n
<b>Proof Techniques:</b> The Structure of Formal Proofs, Direct Proofs, Proof by Counter,
Proof by Contraposition, Proof by Contradiction, Mathematical Induction, Proof of
Necessity and Sufficiency.\n\n
<b>Number Theory:</b> Theorem of Arithmetic, Modular Arithmetic, GCD, LCM, Prime Number,
Congruence, Application of Congruence, Application of Number Theory, Chinese
Remainder Theory.\n\n
<b>Introduction to Counting:</b> Basic Counting Techniques - Inclusion and Exclusion, Pigeon-Hole Principle, Permutation, Combination, Sequence and Summations, Introduction to
Recurrence Relation and Generating Function.\n\n
<b>Introduction to Graphs:</b> Graphs and their Basic Properties - Degree, Path, Cycle, Sub-Graphs, Isomorphism, Euclidian and Hamiltonian Walks, Graph Coloring, Planar Graphs.\n\n
    </string>

    <string name="cse_2103">
      <b>Modeling, Computers and Error Analysis:</b> Mathematical Modeling and Engineering
Problem Solving, Programming and Software, Approximations and Round-Off Errors,
Truncation Errors and the Taylor Series. \n\n
<b>Roots of Equations:</b> Bracketing Methods, Open Methods, Roots of Polynomials,
Linear Algebraic Equations: Gauss Elimination, LU Decomposition and Matrix Inversion,
Gauss-Seidel.\n\n
<b>Optimization:</b> One-dimensional Unconstrained optimization.\n
<b>Curve Fitting:</b> Least-square Regression \n
<b>Interpolation:</b> Interpolation with one and two Independent Variables, Formation of
Different Difference Table, Newton‟s Forward and Backward Difference, Langranges
Interpolation. \n\n
<b>Numerical Differentiation and Integration:</b> Newton-Cotes Integration Formulas,
Integration of Equations, Numerical Differentiation. \n\n
<b>Ordinary Differential Equations:</b> Runge-Kutta Methods, Boundary-Value and
Eigenvalue Problems, Numerical Solution of Partial Differential Equations.\n\n
  </string>

    <string name="eee_2151">
    <b>Semiconductor Diodes:</b> Semiconductor, n-and p-Type Semiconductors, p-n Junction as
a Diodes and their V-I Characteristics, Zener Diode, Half-and Full Wave Rectifiers,
Voltage Regulation using Zener Diodes.\n\n
<b>Filters:</b> Properties of Symmetrical Networks, Characteristics Impedance, Filter
Fundamentals, Different Types of Filters, High Pass, Low Pass, Band Pass and Band
Elimination Filter, Active Filters.\n\n
    <b>Linear Wave Shaping:</b> Diode Wave Shaping Techniques, Clipping and Clamping
Circuits, Comparator Circuits, Switching Circuits; Schmitt Trigger. \n\n
<b>555 Timer: </b>Architecture of 555 Timer, Different Application of 555 Timer, 555 as
Monostable, Bistable and Astable Multivibrators.\n\n
<b>Transistor:</b> Transistor Action, Transistor Biasing, DC Characteristics of CE, CB and CC
Configurations.\n\n
<b>Transistor Amplifiers and Oscillators:</b> CE, CB and CC Amplifiers, Current, Voltage and
Power Gains, Frequency Responses, Principles of Feedback, Positive and Negative
Feedback, and Oscillators. \n\n
</string>

    <string name="math_2113">
        <b>Vector Analysis:</b> Vectors, Differentiation and Integration, Line, Surface and Volume
Integrals, Gradient of a Function, Divergence and Curl of Vector and their Applications,
Physical Significance of Gradient, Divergence and Curl, Vector Identities, Integral Forms
of Gradient, Divergence and Curl, Green‟s Theorem, Stocks Theorem, Gausss
Divergence Theorem.\n\n
<b>Matrix:</b> Definition of Matrices, Equality of two Matrices, Addition, Subtraction and
Multiplication of Matrices, Equivalence of Matrices, Positive and Negative Matrices,
Adjoint of Matrices, Transpose and Inverse of Matrices, Rank and Normal form of
Matrices, System of Linear Equations, Solution of Homogeneous and Non-Homogeneous
Systems, Determination of Eigen Values and Eigen Vectors, Solutions of Matrix
Differential Equations.\n\n
<b>Linear Algebra:</b> Vector Space, Subspace, Sum and Direct Sum, Hilbert Space, Normed
Linear Space, Branch Space, Basis and Dimension. Linear Transformation: Range,
Kernel, Nullity, Singular and Non-Singular Transformation. Linear Operations: Matrix
Representation of a Linear Operator. Change of Basis, Similarity and Linear Mapping.\n\n
    </string>

    <string name="hum_2113">
        <b>Industrial Management:</b> Management: Principle of Management, Management
Functions, Management Skills, Authority and Responsibility, Span of Control, Management
by Objective, Consultative Management, Participative Management, Decision Making,
Manpower Motivation. Human Resources Management: Manpower Planning, Recruitment
and Selection, Employee Training and Development, Performance Appraisal, Wages and Salary
Administration. Production Management: Plant Layout: Definition, Basic Layout Types,
Problem Solving, Problem Solving, Linear Programming.EOQ, Lead Time, Safety Stock,
Re-Order Point. \n\n
<b>Accountancy:</b> Basic Accounting Principles, Objectives of Accounting, Transaction,
Double Entry Systems, Accounts and it‟s Classification, Journals Cash Book, Ledger, Trial
Balance, Financial Statement. Cost Accounts and Objectives; Costs; Classification,
Preparation of Cost Sheet, Cost Volume Profit (CVP) Analysis, Standard Costing, Process
Costing.\n\n
    </string>

    <string name="cse_2201">
        <b>Asymptotic Notations:</b> Complexity Analysis of Algorithms, Worst Case, Best Case and
Average Case.\n\n
<b>Sorting Algorithms:</b> Divide and Conquer Approach, Merge Sort and Quick Sort
Algorithm, Complexity Analysis, Worst and Average Case Analysis, Heap Construction
Algorithm, Heap Sort, Application of Heap: Priority Queue, Decision Tree Model and
(Worst Case) Lower Bound on Sorting, Sorting in Linear Time - Radix Sort, Bucket Sort,
Counting Sort, etc.\n\n
<b>Graph Algorithms:</b> Representation of Graphs, Breadth First Search, Depth First Search,
Minimum Spanning Tree, Kruskal and Prims Algorithm.\n\n
<b>Shortest Path:</b> Dijkstra’s Algorithm, Bellman-Ford Algorithm. Floyd Warshall Algorithm.
Searching Algorithms: Binary Search Trees, Balanced Binary Search Trees, AVL Trees
and Red-Black Trees, B-Trees, Skip Lists, Hashing. Priority Queues, Heaps, Interval
Trees.\n\n
<b>Dynamic Programming:</b> Longest Common Subsequence (LCS), Matrix Chain
Multiplication (MCM), Knapsack Problem, Multistage Graphs.\n\n
<b>Greedy Algorithm:</b> Greedy Algorithm, Activity Selection Problem, Huffman Codes and its
application, Knapsack problem, Tree Vertex Splitting.\n\n
<b>Recurrences and Backtracking:</b> Recurrences, NP-Hard and NP-Complete Problems,
Backtracking, n-Queen Problem, Branch and Bounds.\n\n
<b>Reducibility between Problems and NP-completeness:</b> Lower Bound Theory,
Discussion of Different NP-Complete Problems like Satisfiability, Clique, Vertex Cover,
Independent Set, Hamiltonian Cycle, TSP, Knapsack, Set Cover, Bin Packing, etc.
Computational Geometry, Line Segment Properties, Convex Hull, Graham Scan Algorithm
of Convex Hull.\n\n
    </string>

    <string name="cse_2203">
        <b>Information and Digital Systems:</b> Introduction to Digital Systems, Number Systems,
Weighted and Non-Weighted Codes, Error Detection Code, Binary Addition and
Subtraction, 2‟s Compliment Methods.\n\n
<b>Boolean Algebra and Combinational Logic Circuits:</b> Digital Logic, Boolean Algebra,
Boolean Function, Canonical Forms, Karnaugh Maps, Minimization of Boolean Functions,
Logic Gates and their Truth Tables, Design Methodologies, Combinational Logic Circuit
Design, Arithmetic and Data Handling Logic Circuits. Decoders, Encoders, Multiplexer,
Demultiplexer.\n\n
<b>Flip Flop and Sequential Logic Circuits:</b> Transistor Latch, NAND Gate Latch, NOR
Gate Latch, D Latch. Clock Signals and Clocked Ffs: Clocked SR, JK and D Flip-Flops,
Master/Slave JK FF, Timing Diagram of Different Ffs, Edge-Triggered and Level-Triggered
Timing Diagrams., Counters, Registers, Memory Devices and their Applications. \n\n
<b>Technology Parameters:</b> Fan In, Fan Out, Propagation Delay, Power Dissipation and
Noise Immunity.\n\n
<b>Others:</b> Diode Logic Gates, Transistor Gates, MOS Gates, Logic Families: TTL and
CMOS Logic with Operation Details\n\n
    </string>

    <string name="cse_2205">
        <b>Finite State Machine:</b> Fundamental of Finite State Machine, State Equivalence and
Minimization of Machine, Incompletely Specified Machine and Minimal Machine, Merger
Graph and Compatibility Graph, Finite Memory and Definite Memory Machine, Information
Lossless Machine and Inverse Machine.\n\n
<b>Finite Automata:</b> Introduction to Finite Automata, Structural Representations, Automata
and Complexity, an Informal Picture of Finite Automata, Deterministic Finite Automata,
Non-Deterministic Finite Automata, an Application (i.e. Text Search or other), Finite
Automata with Epsilon-Transitions.\n\n
<b>Regular Expressions and Languages:</b> Regular Expressions, Finite Automata and
Regular Expression, Application of Regular Expressions, Algebraic Laws for Regular
Expressions; Closure Properties of Regular Language, Decision Properties of Regular
Languages, Equivalence and Minimization of Automata.\n\n
<b>Context-Free Grammar and Languages:</b> Context-free Grammars, Parse Trees,
Application of Context-Free Grammars, Ambiguity in Grammars and Languages, Normal
Forma for Context-Free Grammars, The Pumping Lemma for Context-Free Languages,
Closure Properties of Context-Free Languages, Decision Properties of CFLs.\n\n
<b>Pushdown Automata:</b> Definition of the Pushdown Automata, the Languages of a PDA,
Equivalence of PDA‟s and CFG‟s, Deterministic Pushdown Automata.\n\n
<b>Introduction to Turing Machines:</b> The Turing Machine, Programming Techniques for
Turing Machines, Extensions to the Basic Turing Machine, Restricted Turing Machines,
Turing Machines and Computers.\n\n
<b>Undecidability:</b> A language that is not recursively enumerable, an undecidable problem
that is RE, undecidable problems about turing machines, post‟s correspondence problem,
other undecidable problems. \n\n
    </string>

    <string name="eee_2251">
        <b>DC Machines:</b> Operation and Performance Characteristics of Generators and Motors.
Starting, Speed Control and Braking of Motors. Different Application of DC Motors.
AC Machines: Transformer: Principle of Operation of Transformer. Single Phase
Induction Motors and its Methods Of Starting.\n\n
<b>Synchronous Machines and Motors:</b> Principles of Operation and Equivalent Circuit.
Method of Synchronization. Special Motors: Stepper Motor, Servomotor, Brush Less
Motors.\n\n
<b>Measuring Instruments:</b> Electromechanical and Electronic Meters and their Uses.
Extension of Instrument Range.\n\n
<b>Transducers:</b> Different Types of Transducers and their Principle of Operations: Position
and Displacement Transducers, Potentiometer, Linear Variable Differential Transformers
(LVDT), Pressure Transducer, Temperature Transducer, Optical Transducer, Ultrasonic
Transducer; Humidity Transducer, Hall Effect Transducer, and Speed Transducer.\n\n
    </string>

    <string name="math_2213">
        <b>Complex Variable :</b> Complex Number Systems, General Functions of a Complex
Variable, Limits and Continuity of a Function of Complex Variable and Related Theorems,
Complex Differentiation and the Cauchy-Riemenn Equations, Infinite Series,
Convergence, Line Integral, Cauchy Integral Theorem, Cauchy Integral Formula,
Liouvilles Theorem, Taylors and Laurents Theorems, Singular Points, Residue, Cauchys
Residue Theorem, Contour Integration.\n\n
<b>Differential Equations:</b> Series Solution: Singular Points, Series Solutions: Frobenius
Method, Bessels and Legenders Differential Equations.\n\n
<b>Partial Differential Equation:</b> Partial Differential Equations, Solution of First Order Partial
Differential Equation by Lagrange and Charpit Methods, Solution of Laplace Equation and
Wave Equation.\n\n
<b>Harmonic Analysis and Laplace Transform:</b> Fourier Series and Fourier
Transformations and its Applications to Solve Boundary Value Problems. Laplace
Transforms, Inverse Laplace Transforms, Solution of Differential Equation by Laplace
Transforms.\n\n
    </string>

    <string name="cse_3100">
        Students will Work in Groups or Individually to Develop Web based Applications and
Design a Web Site by Adding Client Side and Server Side Scripting and Interfacing the
Web Applications to a Database.\n\n
    </string>

    <string name="cse_3101">
        <b>Concepts of Database Systems:</b> Files and Databases, Database Management Systems;
Transaction Management, Structure of a DBMS, Applications.\n\n
<b>Entity-Relationship Concepts:</b> Entity Types, Entity Set, Attribute and Key, Relationships,
Relation Types, Entity Relationship, ER Modeling, ER Diagrams, Database Design using
ER Diagrams, Enhanced Entity-Relationship (EER) Model.\n\n
<b>Normalization:</b> Normal Forms, Normalized Relations and Database Performance; DeNormalization.\n\n
Relational Model: Structure of Relational Databases, Relational Algebra, Relational
Algebra Operations, Modification of the Database, Introduction to Views, Pitfalls in
Relational Database Design.\n\n
<b>SQL:</b> Data Definition Language, Data Manipulation Language, Basics of SQL, Query
Designing in SQL using Aggregate Functions and Nested Queries, Embedded SQL,
Triggers, Procedures; Indexes; Declarative Constrains and Database Triggers.\n\n
<b>Concurrency Control:</b> Lock based Protocols, Timestamp based Protocols, Validation
based Protocols, Deadlock.\n\n
        <b>Recovery System:</b> Failure Classification, Storage Structure, Recovery and Atomicity,
Log-based Recovery, Recovery with Concurrent Transactions, Advanced Recovery
Techniques, RAID Model.\n\n
<b>Advanced Database Management Systems:</b> No SQL Systems, Distributed Systems,
Object-Oriented System, Temporal, Database Security, Data Warehousing and Data
Mining, Database Administration and Tuning. \n\n
    </string>

    <string name="cse_3103">
        <b>Fundamental:</b> Representation of Signals in Time and Frequency Domain, Properties of
Fourier Transform, Delta Function, Auto-Correlation and Cross-Correlation.\n\n
<b>Data Communication and Network Model:</b> Data Communication, Fundamental of
Networks, History of the Internet, Protocols and Standards.\n\n
<b>Signal and System, Transmission Media, Interfaces:</b> Analog and Digital Data, Periodic
Analog Signals, Digital Signals, Transmission Impairment, Data Rate Limits and
Performance.\n\n
<b>Digital and Analog Transmission:</b> Digital to Digital Conversion, Line Encoding
Schemes, Block Coding, Scrambling, Analog to Digital Conversion, Transmission
Modes, Digital to Analog Conversion, Bandwidth Utilization, Analog to Digital Conversion.\n\n
<b>Multiplexing, Spreading and Switching:</b> Multiplexing, Spread Spectrum, Packet-Switched Data Networks, Circuit Switched Data Networks, Virtual Circuit Networks.
Transmission Medium: Guided Media and Unguided Media. \n\n
    </string>

    <string name="cse_3105">
        <b>Introduction:</b> Introduction to Software and its Nature, Software Engineering Methods,
Professional and Ethical Responsibility of a Software Engineer.\n\n
<b>Software Process Model:</b> Different Types of Software Process Model and their
Implementations, Costs of Software Engineering.\n\n
<b>Software Requirement Analysis:</b> Software Requirements Analysis and their
Applications, Software Prototyping, Basic Concepts of Different Formal Software
Specification.\n\n
<b>Design of Software:</b> Software Design and its Different Techniques, Software
Configuration Managements. System Structuring, Control Models, Modular
Decomposition, Domain-Specific Architecture. \n\n
<b>Software Testing:</b> Software Validation and Verification: Verification and Validation
Planning, Softwares Testing Strategies and Different Type of Testing Techniques, Art of
Debugging.\n\n
<b>Software Quality Assurance:</b> Management and its Quality Assurance, Software
Cognitive Fundamentals, Concepts of Software Reengineering and Web Engineering. \n\n
<b>Advance Topics:</b> Software Reliability Metrics, Software Reliability Specification,
Statistical Testing and Reliability Growth Modeling, Use of CASE Tools and Technological
Support in Engineering Software, Introduction to Unified Modeling Language–UML.\n\n
    </string>

    <string name="cse_3107">
        <b>Introduction:</b> Statistics and its Importance, Population and Sample, Variable and
Constants, Statistical Data, Data Collection and Presentation, Construction of Frequency
Distribution and Graphical Presentation.\n\n
<b>Measures of Central Tendency:</b> Arithmetic Mean, Geometric Mean, Harmonic Mean,
Median, Mode, Weighted Mean.\n\n
<b>Measures of Dispersion:</b> Range, Standard Deviation, Variance, Moments, Skewness
and Kurtosis. \n\n
        <b>Correlation Theory:</b> Linear Correlation and its Measures and Significance, Rank
Correlation. \n\n
<b>Regression Analysis:</b> Linear and Non-Linear Regression, Least-Square Method of Curve
Fittings. \n\n
<b>Probability:</b> Elementary Concepts, Laws of Probability – Additive and Multiplicative Law,
Conditional Probability and Bay‟s Theorem, Random Variables, Mathematical Expectation.
Probability Distributions: Binomial Distribution, Poisson Distribution and Normal
Distribution. \n\n
<b>Queuing Theory:</b> Stochastic Processes, Discrete Time Markov Chain and Continuous
Time Markov Chain. Birth-Death Process in Queuing. Queuing Models:
M/M/1,M/M/C,M/G/1,M/D/1,G/M/1 Solution of Network of Queue-Closed Queuing Models
and Approximate Models. Application of Queuing Models in Computer Science. \n\n
    </string>

    <string name="cse_3109">
        <b>Microcomputer System:</b> Introduction to Different Types of Microprocessors and its
Applications, Organization of Intel 8086/8088 Microprocessor, the Component of
Microcomputer System, I/O Device, Interrupt Structures, I/O Interfacing, DMA, CoProcessors, RISC Processors, Power PC Processor, CISC Processor, Direct Video RAM
Accessing, Memory Module.\n\n
<b>Introduction of Assembly Language:</b> Program Structure and its Components, Few
Basic Instruction, Input/Output Instruction.\n\n
<b>Flag Register and Flow Control:</b> The Flag Register, Flow Control Instructions,
Conditional and Unconditional Jumps, Branching and Looping Structures.
Logic and Arithmetic Operation: Logic, Shift and Rotate Instruction, Multiplication and
Division Instructions.\n\n
<b>Arrays and Data Structure:</b> Arrays and Related Addressing Modes, DUP Operator,
Register Indirect Modes, Based and Indexed Addressing Modes, Basic Stack Operations,
Procedures Declaration, Communication between Procedures, Calling a Procedure. \n\n
<b>String Manipulation:</b> The String Instructions, Director Flag, Moving a String, Storing a
String, Loading a String, Scanning a String, Comparing Strings, Substring Operation.\n\n

    </string>

    <string name="cse_3112">
        <b>Introduction:</b> Issues of Technical Writing and Effective Oral Presentation in Computer
Science and Engineering.\n\n
<b>Writing Issues:</b> Writing Styles of Definitions, Propositions, Theorems and Proofs;
Preparation of Reports, Research Papers.\n\n
<b>Thesis and Books:</b> Abstract, Preface, Contents, Bibliography and Index; Writing of Book
Reviews and Referee Reports.\n\n
<b>Writing and Presentation Tools:</b> LATEX; Diagram Drawing Software; Presentation
Tools.\n\n
    </string>

    <string name="cse_3200">
        Students will Work in Groups or Individually to Develop High Quality Software/Projects
Including New I/O Drivers or Similar Projects Involving Operating Systems Modules in
Different Types of Data Base Systems or Project Oriented and Visual Languages,
Students will Writes Structure Program and use Proper Documentation.\n\n
    </string>

    <string name="cse_3201">
        <b>Introduction to Operating System:</b> Operating System Concepts, its Role in Computer
Systems, Computer System Structure, Fundamental of Different Types of Computer
System, Operating System Structure and Operation, Protection and Security.\n\n
<b>Process Management:</b> Process Concept, Model and Implementation, Process State,
Process Scheduling, Inter-Process Communication (IPC), Multiprocessing and
Timesharing, Interaction between Process and Operating System; CPU Scheduling:
        Scheduling Concepts, Scheduling Criteria, Scheduling Algorithms (SJF, FIFO, Round
Robin, etc.). \n\n
<b>Memory Management:</b> Memory Portioning, with and without Swapping, Virtual Memory –
Paging and Segmentation, Demand Paging, Page Replacement Algorithms,
Implementation.\n\n
<b>File Systems:</b> FS Services, Disk Space Management, Directory and Data Structures;
Deadlocks and Case Study: Modeling, Detection and Recovery, Prevention and
Avoidance; Case Study of Some Operating Systems.\n\n
<b>Others:</b> Introduction to the Different Smart Device Operating System and their Usage.\n\n
    </string>

    <string name="cse_3203">
        <b>Introduction to Computer Architecture:</b> Internal Structure of Processor/CPU–Registers,
PC, ALU, CU, etc. Bus Architecture and Processor Interaction with Memory and
Peripherals, Memory Hierarchy in Terms of Cache Memory, Main Memory, Secondary
Storage, Memory Organization into Bytes and Words; Big-Endian and Little-Endian
Organization, Computer Peripherals, Introduction to Von Neumann SISD Organization,
RISC and CISC Machines.\n\n
<b>Review:</b> Representation of Strings, Binary and Hex Integer Representations and
Conversions, Signed and Unsigned Formats; 2s Complement, Computer Integer
Arithmetic, Fixed-Point Arithmetic, IEEE Floating Point Representation and Arithmetic.\n\n
<b>Process and Control:</b> Fetch-Execute Cycle, Encoding and Decoding of MIPS Machine
Instructions, the MIPS CPU Instruction Set Syntax and Semantics, Addressing Modes,
MIPS Assembly Language Programming, Register Usage Conventions, use of Stack and
Stack-Frame for Supporting Function Calling with Parameters, Operating System Calls
and I/O Operations. CPU and its Instruction Sets Design. \n\n
        <b>Application HDL and FPGA for Microcomputer Design:</b> Introduction to FPGA and
HDL/VHDL for Digital Design Implementation. \n\n

    </string>

    <string name="cse_3205">
        <b>Introduction:</b> Definition, uses of Computer Networks, Network Topology, Network Media,
Network Devices, Different Types of Network: LAN, MAN, WAN etc.\n\n
<b>IP Addressing:</b> Classification of IP Addressing, Subnet Mask, CIDR, Private IP Address,
Public IP Address, Sub Netting, VLSM etc.\n\n
<b>Network Model:</b> OSI Reference Model, TCP/IT Reference Model, ATM Reference Model,
Functions of the Layers of Different Models, Network Protocols Working at Different
Layers.\n\n
<b>Data Link Layer Design Issues and Framing:</b> Character Count, Byte Stuffing, Bit
Stuffing, Error Detection: Cyclic Redundancy Check, Parity Bit Checking and Correction:
Hamming Code, Windowing Protocols: Go Back N ARQ, Selective Repeat ARQ,
Elementary Data Link Protocols, High-Level Data Link Control, Point to Point Protocol, the
Medium Access Control Sub-Layer.\n\n
<b>Multiple Access:</b> Random Access; ALOHA, CSMA, CSMA/CD, CSMA/CA, Channelized
Access, CDMA, TDMA, FDMA, Controlled Access, Reservation, Poling, Token Passing,
Ethernet, Wireless Lans and Bluetooth.\n\n
<b>Switching:</b> Circuit Switching, Packet Switching, Message Switching, Routing
Algorithms, Virtual Circuit and Datagram, Congestion Control Algorithms, Quality of
Service, Internetworking, Internetworking Devices etc.\n\n
<b>Network Layer Protocols:</b> Address Resolution Protocol, Internet Protocol, Internet
Control, Message Protocol, IPV6, Routing Information Protocol, Open Shortest Path
First, Border Gateway Protocol, User Datagram Protocol, Transmission Control Protocol.\n\n
<b>Network Security:</b> Cryptography, Substitution Cipher, Transposition Cipher, One Time
Pads, Public Key Cryptography, Encryption and Decryption, Authentication Protocol 1.0
to 5.0, Digital Signature, Key Distribution Center, Different Symmetric Key Algorithm,
Certificate Authority, DNS, Electronic Mail, World Wide Web.\n\n
<b>Others:</b> HTTP and Recent Advances in Internet Protocols, Web Server Performance,
Proxy Servers, Load Balancing in Web Servers, IP Security, Queuing Models for Networks
and Protocols, Real Time Protocols such as RTP, RTCP and RTSP, Voice over IP, Cloud
Computing. \n\n
    </string>

    <string name="cse_3207">
        <b>Microprocessor Based System Design:</b> Hardware and Software Interfacing in
Microcomputer System Design, Hardware and I/O Design, Building, Debugging, Testing
and Linking Program Modules, Programming EPROM. \n\n
        <b>Interfacing Components:</b> 8284A Programmable Timer, Bus Architecture, Bus Timing,
8286 Transceiver Device, 8282 Latches, 8288 Bus Controller, Characteristics of Memory
and I/O Interface, Synchronous and Asynchronous Communication, Serial I/O Interface,
8251A Communication Interface, 8255A Programmable Peripheral Interface.\n\n
<b>Interrupt System:</b> Sources of Interrupt, Types of Interrupt, Handling Interrupt Request,
Interrupt Vector and Table, 8259A Priority Interrupt Controller, Daisy Chain. \n\n
<b>I/O Controller and Peripheral Components:</b> Interfacing ICs of I/O Devices, I/O Ports,
Programmable Peripheral Interface, DMA Controller I.E. 8237A DMA Controller, Interrupt
Controller, Communication Interface, Interval Timer, etc. \n\n
<b>Memory Device:</b> Memory Terminology, CPU-Memory Connections, ROM Architectures
and Time Diagram, Different Type of ROM, Flash Memory, RAM Architectures and Time
Diagram, Different Type of RAM and Read/Write Cycle, Programmable Logic Device
Architectures. \n\n
<b>Multi-processor Configurations:</b> Co-Processor Configurations, Numeric Data
Processor, I/O Processors.\n\n
<b>Analog and Digital Interface:</b> Sensors, Transducers, D/A Interface, A/D Interface, AD
and DA Converters Related Chips, High Power Devices. \n\n
    </string>

    <string name="cse_3209">
        <b>Fundamental:</b> Definition of Al, Historical Development of Al, Application of Al.\n\n
<b>Production Systems:</b> Introduction of Product System, Production Rules, the Working
Memory, the Control Unit Interpretation, Conflict Resolution Strategies, Alternative
Approach for Conflict Resolution, Types of Production Systems, Forward Versus
Backward Production Systems, Knowledge Base Optimization in a Production System.\n\n
<b>General Problem Solving Approaches:</b> Breadth First Search, Depth First Search,
Iterative Deepening Search, Hill Climbing, Simulated Annealing, Heuristic Search, A*
Algorithm, Adversary Search, the Minimax Algorithm, Constraint Satisfaction Problems. \n\n
<b>Logic and Structural Knowledge Representation:</b> Propositional Logic, First-Order
Logic, Resolution Principle, Frames, Semantic-Nets, Petri Nets, Relational Data Model.\n\n
<b>Reasoning under Uncertainty:</b> Bayesian Reasoning, Fuzzy Knowledge, Probability
Theory, Dempster-Shafer Theory, Fuzzy Set Theory, Expert Systems.\n\n
<b>Machine Learning and Natural Language Processing:</b> Naive Bayes Algorithm,
Syntactic Semantics and Pragmatic, Top-Down Passing, Bottom-Up Pursing, Lexicon.\n\n
<b>Programming Languages for Al Research:</b> Historical Overview, Features of Al
Programming Languages, Major Al Programming Languages LISP, PROLOG,
Implementation of AI Algorithms Through PROLOG.\n\n
    </string>

    <string name="cse_4100">
        Study of Problems in the Field of Computer Science and Engineering.
N.B. The Project/Thesis Topic Selected in this Course is to be continued in the CSE 4000
Course.\n\n
    </string>

    <string name="cse_4101">
        <b>Introduction to Compiler:</b> Compiler Structure, Analysis-Synthesis Model of Compilation,
Various Phases of a Compiler, Tool based Approach to Compiler Construction, Complier Compliers and Translator Writing Systems.
Lexical Analysis: Interface with Input, Parser and Symbol Table, Token, Lexeme and
Patterns, Difficulties in Lexical Analysis, Error Reporting, Implementation, Regular
Definition, Transition Diagrams, Lex.\n\n
<b>Syntax Analysis:</b> CFGs, Ambiguity, Associativity, Precedence, Top Down Parsing,
Recursive Descent Parsing, Transformation on the Grammars, Predictive Parsing, Bottom
Up Parsing, Operator Precedence Grammars, LR Parsers (SLR, LALR, LR), YACC.
Syntax Directed Definitions: Inherited and Synthesized Attributes, Dependency Graph,
Evaluation Order, Bottom Up and Top Down Evaluation of Attributes, L- and S-Attributed
Definitions.\n\n
<b>Type Checking:</b> Type System, Type Expressions, Structural and Name Equivalence of
Types, Type Conversion, Overloaded Functions and Operators, Polymorphic Functions.\n\n
<b>Run Time System:</b> Storage Organization, Activation Tree, Activation Record, Parameter
Passing, Symbol Table, Dynamic Storage Allocation, and Heap Storage Management.
Intermediate Code Generation: Intermediate Representations, Translation of
Declarations, Assignments, Control Flow, Boolean Expressions and Procedure Calls,
Implementation Issues.\n\n
<b>Code Generation and Instruction Selection:</b> Issues, Basic Blocks and Flow Graphs,
Register Allocation, Code Generation, Dag Representation of Programs, Code Generation
from Dags, Peep Hole Optimization, Code Generator Generators, Specifications of
Machine.\n\n
    </string>

    <string name="cse_4103">
        <b>Introduction:</b> Signals, Systems and Signal Processing, Classification of Signals, the
Concept of Frequency in Continuous Time and Discrete Time Signals, Analog to Digital
and Digital to Analog Conversion, Sampling and Quantization.\n\n
<b>Discrete Time Signals and Systems:</b> Discrete Time Signals, Discrete Time Systems,
Analysis of Discrete Time Linear Time Invariant Systems. Discrete Time Systems
Described by Difference Equations, Implementation of Discrete Time Systems, Correlation
and Convolution of Discrete Time Signals.\n\n
<b>The Z-Transform:</b> Introduction, Definition of the Z-Transform, Z-Transform and ROC of
Infinite Duration Sequence, Properties of Z-Transform Inversion of the Z-Transform, the
One-Sided Z-Transform.\n\n
<b>Frequency Analysis of Signals and Systems:</b> Frequency Analysis of Continuous Time
Signals, Frequency Analysis of Discrete Time Signals, Properties of Fourier Transform of
Discrete Time Signals, Frequency Domain Characteristics of Linear Time Invariant
System, Linear Time Invariant Systems as Frequency Selective Filters, Inverse Systems
and De-convolution.\n\n
<b>Discrete Fourier Transform (DFT):</b> Discrete Fourier Series (DFS), Properties of DFS,
Discrete Fourier Transformation (DFT), Properties and Application of DFT.\n\n
<b>Fast Fourier Transform Algorithms:</b> FFT Algorithms, Applications of FFT Algorithm.
Digital Filter Design Techniques: Differential and Difference Equations, Digital Transfer
Functions, Frequency Response, Digital Filter Realization Scheme, Finite Impulse
Response (FIR) Infinite Impulse Response (IIR) Filter Design.\n\n
<b>Application of DSP: </b>Speech Processing, Analysis and Coding, Matlab Application to
DSP.\n\n
    </string>

    <string name="cse_4105">
        <b>Digital Image Fundamentals:</b> Different Types of Digital Images, Sampling and
Quantization, Imaging Geometry, Image Acquisition Systems. \n\n
        <b>Bi-level Image Processing:</b> Basic Concepts of Digital Distances, Distance Transform,
Medial Axis Transform, Component Labeling, Thinning, Morphological Processing,
Extension to Grey Scale Morphology. \n\n
<b>Binarization of Grey Level Images:</b> Histogram of Grey Level Images, Optimal
Thresholding using Bayesian Classification, Multilevel Thresholding.\n\n
<b>Detection of Edges :</b> First Order and Second Order Edge Operators, Multi-Scale Edge
Detection, Cannys Edge Detection Algorithm, Hough Transform for Detecting Lines and
Curves, Edge Linking. \n\n
<b>Images Enhancement:</b> Point Processing, Spatial Filtering, Frequency Domain Filtering,
Multi-Spectral Image Enhancement, Image Restoration.\n\n
<b>Image Segmentation:</b> Segmentation of Grey Level Images, Water Shade Algorithm for
Segmenting Grey Level Image. Image Representation and Description, Recognition and
Interpretation.\n\n
<b>Image Compression:</b> Lossy and Lossless Compression Schemes, Prediction based
Compression Schemes, Vector Quantization, Sub-Band Encoding Schemes, JPEG
Compression Standard, Fractal Compression Scheme, Wavelet Compression Scheme.\n\n

    </string>

    <string name="cse_4107">
        <b>Application Development Policy and Strategies:</b> Planning of Information System,
Policy in Information System Development, Strategies for Achieving Information System
Goals.\n\n
<b>Application System Development Life Cycle:</b> Phases in Application System
Development, Interrelationship among Each Phase.\n\n
<b>Feasibility Assessment:</b> Problems and Needs in Information System Development,
Preliminary Application Requirements Determination, Feasibility Assessment: Economic,
Technical, Operational and Schedule Feasibility.\n\n
<b>Information Requirements Determination:</b> Strategies for Obtaining Information
Requirements, Technique for Information Requirements Determination, Methods for
Providing Assurance that Requirement are Correct and Complete. \n\n
<b>Structured Systems Analysis:</b> Steps in Structured Systems Analysis, Activity Diagrams
and Related Documentation, Data Dictionary, Problem Analysis, Structured Walk
Through. \n\n
<b>Systems Design Methodology:</b> Check List Methodology, Process-Oriented
Methodology, Application Generator, Structured Design, Program Development and
Testing: Structured Programming and Method for Testing.\n\n

    </string>

    <string name="cse_4109">
        <b>Introduction:</b> Introduction to Unix Programming.
Unix Environment: Command Line, Globbing, I/O Redirection, Piping, Basic Commands,
Memory Layout.\n\n
<b>Debugging:</b> GDB, Valgrind, Essential X86, Fork, Exec, Wait, Process Status, Bit
Manipulation, Sending Signals Unix I/O Implementing I/O Redirection, Piping Directories
and Files. Walking a Directory Tree, Exploring Attributes. Implementing Ls-L. Permissions,
File Owner / Group, Time-Stamps. Signals and Signal Handling Design / Implementation
of Sleep Process Relationships Backgrounding. Popen / Pclose Midterm Terminal
Handling Review Midterm Networking Client / Server. I/O Multiplexing.\n\n
<b>Multi-threading:</b> Basics, Mutual Exclusion Multi-Threading: Bounded Buffers, Condition
Variables Multi-Threading: Deadlocks Non-Blocking I/O. Regular Expressions. Sys V IPC.
Semaphores and Shared Memory. Shell Scripting.\n\n
    </string>

    <string name="cse_4111">
        <b>System Design:</b> Designing I/O System; I/O Devices; Designing Microprocessor based
System with Interfacing Chips.\n\n
<b>Programmable Design:</b> Programmable Peripheral Interface (Interface to A/D and D/A
Converter); Keyboard/Display Interface; Programmable Timer; Programmable Interrupt
Controller, DMA Controller.\n\n
<b>Memory Design:</b> Design using MSI and LSI Components; Design of Memory Subsystem
using SRAM and DRAM.\n\n
<b>Design of Various Components of a Computer:</b> ALU, Memory and Control Unit,
Hardwired and Micro Programmed; Microprocessor based Designs; Computer BUS
Standards; Design Special Purpose Controllers.\n\n
    </string>

    <string name="cse_4113">
        <b>Simulation Modeling Basics:</b> Systems, Models and Simulation; Classification of
Simulation Models; Steps in a Simulation Study.\n\n
<b>Concepts in Discrete-Event Simulation:</b> Event-Scheduling vs. Process-Interaction
Approaches, Time-Advance Mechanism, Organization of a Discrete-Event Simulation
Model; Continuous Simulation Models; Combined Discreet-continuous models; Monte
Carlo Simulation; Simulation of Queuing Systems.\n\n
<b>Building Valid and Credible Simulation Models:</b> Validation Principles and Techniques,
Statistical Procedures for Comparing Real-World Observations and Simulated Outputs,
Input Modeling; Generating Random Numbers and Random Variates; Output Analysis.
Simulation Languages; Analysis and Modeling of Some Practical Systems\n\n
    </string>

    <string name="cse_4115">
        <b>Introduction to Wireless Networks:</b> Wireless Access Networks, Wireless Mesh
Networks, Personal Area Networks (Wireless Sensor Networks, Body Area Networks,
Lowpan, and Bluetooth), Wireless and Mobile Ad Hoc Networks, Challenged Networks
(Dtns,Vanets).\n\n
<b>Wireless MAC Protocols:</b> IEEE 802.11, IEEE 802.11e, IEEE 802.11n, IEEE 802.11s,
IEEE 802.15.4, S-MAC, B-MAC, IEEE 802.22/20, IEEE 802.16d/e.\n\n
<b>Wireless Routing:</b> Routing Matrix – ETX, ETT, WCETT, Air Time Metric, Routing
Protocols – AODV, DSR, DSDV, HWMP, Sensor Network Routing, VANET Routing etc.\n\n
<b>Others:</b> Wireless Transport Protocols; Wireless TCP and its Variants, Hop by Hop
Congestion Control, Rate based Congestion Control etc. Quality of Service in Wireless
Networks.\n\n
    </string>

    <string name="cse_4117">
        <b>Multithreaded Computing:</b> Basic Concepts: Processes, Threads, Scheduling,
Multithreaded Programming, Thread Synchronization: Semaphores, Locks, Monitors,
Concurrency Issues: Deadlock, Starvation , Multi-Core Computers.\n\n
<b>Networked Computers:</b> Basic Concepts: Client-Server, Connections, Datagrams,
Application Protocol Design, Client-Side Socket Programming, Server-Side Socket
Programming, Datagram Programming.\n\n
        <b>Network Protocols and Security:</b> Physical/Data Link/Network/Transport/Application
Layers, Network Security.\n\n
<b>Distributed Systems:</b> Architectures: Two-Tier, Multi-Tier, Peer-To-Peer, Many-To-Many,
Middleware: Distributed Objects, Web Services.\n\n
<b>Parallel Computing:</b> Architectures: SMP, Cluster, Hybrid, Grid, GPGPU ,Middleware:
Openmp, MPI, Grid Middleware.\n\n
    </string>

    <string name="cse_4119">
        <b>Process and Model:</b> Introduction to Human-Computer Interaction (HCI), Human
Information Processing Systems, Models of Interaction, Approaches to HCI, User
Interface, HCI in Software Process, Cognitive Models.\n\n
<b>Issues and Requirements:</b> Socio-organizational Issues and Stakeholders Requirements,
Communication and Collaboration Models, Task Analysis, Dialog Notation and Design,
Groupware, CSCW and Social Issues. \n\n
<b>User System Interaction:</b> Analysis and Design, User Interface Design, Interface
Technique and Technology, Case Studies.\n\n
    </string>

    <string name="cse_4121">
        <b>Evolution of Switching Systems:</b> The Role of Switching Systems in Telecommunication
Networks, Step by Step and Crossbar, Stored Program Control (SPC), Digital Switching,
ATM Switching.\n\n
<b>Switching System Architecture:</b> Subscriber and Line Interface, Switching Network:
Matrix and Channel Graph Representations, Blocking, Non-Blocking, and Rearrangeable
Networks, Control Unit, Operation and Maintenance, Switching Process: Call Detecting,
Number Analysis, Call Routing, Supervision, and Metering, Signaling Equipment.\n\n

<b>Hardware and Software Structure of the Digital Switch:</b> Time Switches and Space
Switches, Path Searching, Processor Systems Architecture and Functions, Reliability and
Fault Recovery, Man Machine Interface (MMI), Examples of the Present Digital Switching
Systems.\n\n
    </string>

    <string name="cse_4123">
        <b>Introduction to Control System:</b> Conventional Control System, Steady State Response
to Step, Ramp, and Parabolic Inputs, Transient Response, Poles and Zeros, Frequency
Response from Pole-Zero Diagram, Routh‟s Stability Criterion; Block Diagrams,
Canonical Forms, Transfer Functions and Signal Flow Graph, Root Locus, Frequency
Response, Nyquist‟s Stability Criterion. \n\n
<b>Modern Control System:</b> Introduction, State Variable Analysis, Controllability and
Observability, Application of Eigen Value, Linear Control System Design by State
Feedback. \n\n
<b>Controller Design:</b> On-Off, Fuzzy, P, PI, PD and PID Types, Introduction to
Programmable Logic Controllers (PLC), Temperature Control System, Position Control
System.\n\n
    </string>

    <string name="cse_4201">
        <b>Introduction:</b> History, Application of Computer Graphics (Computer Aided Design
Animation), a Survey of Graphics I/O Devices and Types.\n\n
        <b>Graphics Software Design:</b> Survey of Desired Function, Toward a Universal Graphic
Language. Display Files, Databases for Pictorial Applications.\n\n
<b>Graphics Techniques:</b> Point-Plotting Techniques, Line Drawing, Geometric
Transformations, Windowing and Clipping, Raster Graphics.\n\n
<b>Hardware for Computer Graphics:</b> Typical Small and Large System, Graphic Terminals,
Plotters, Graphic Display Processors, Device Independent Graphics Systems.\n\n
<b>Graphics Software:</b> A Simple Graphic Package, Segmented Display Files, Geometric
Models, Picture Structure.\n\n
<b>Interactive Graphics:</b> Input Techniques, Event Handling, Three-Dimensional Graphics,
Curves and Surfaces, 3-D Transformation. \n\n
<b>Hidden Surface Problem:</b> Back Face Removal, Hidden-Line Removal Curved Surfaces,
Describing Points, Lines and Polygons, Some Hints for Building Polygonal Models, Color
Perception, RGBA and Color Index Mode, Dithering, Blending, 3-D Blending with the
Depth Buffer, Antialiasing, Fog, Fog Equations, the OpenGL ARB.\n\n
<b>API Specifies:</b> Data Types, Function Naming Conventions, Platform Independence,
Drawing Shapes with OpenGL, Animation with OpenGL and GLUT.\n\n
<b>Drawing in Space:</b> Lines, Points and Polygons. \n
<b>Co-ordinate Transformations:</b> Understanding Transformations, Matrix Munching
Projections, Matrix Manipulation Color Lighting and Materials, Texture Mapping.\n\n
    </string>

    <string name="cse_4203">
        <b>Introductory Concept:</b> Introduction Human Brain Mechanism, Neural Machine
Intelligence.\n\n
<b>Fundamental Concept of Neural Network:</b> Basic Models of Artificial Neuron, Activation
Function, Network Architecture, Neural Network Viewed as Directed Graph, Basic
Learning Rules, Overview of Perceptrons, Single Layer of Perceptrons, Mathematical
Model of Single Layer Perceptrons, Perceptrons Learning Algorithm, Delta Learning Rule,Multi-Layer Perceptrons, Back Propagation Learning Algorithm, Mathematical Model of
MLP Network.\n\n
<b>Function Approximation:</b> Basis Function Network, Radial Basis Function Networks
(RBF), MLP vs. RBF Networks, Support Vector Machine (SVM).\n\n
<b>Competitive Network and Associative Memory Network:</b> Adaptive Resonance Theory
(ART), ART-1 Architecture and Algorithm, Kohonen Self-Organizing Maps (SOMs), Linear
Feed-Forward Associative Memory Network, Recurrent Associative Memory Network,
Bidirectional Associative Memory Network (BAM), Hopfield Networks. \n\n
<b>Fuzzy System:</b> Introduction to Fuzzy System, Fuzzy Relations, Fuzzy Numbers,
Linguistic Description and their Analytical Form, Fuzzy Control. \n\n
<b>Defuzzification:</b> Defuzzification Methods, Centroid Method, Center of Sum Method, Mean
of Maxima Defuzzification, Applications, Equilibrium of Learning System, Concept of
Neuro-Fuzzy and Neuro-GA Network.\n\n
<b>Genetic Algorithm:</b> Basic Concepts, Offspring, Encoding, Reproduction, Crossover,
Mutation Operator, Application of GA.\n\n
    </string>

    <string name="cse_4207">
        <b>VLSI Design Methodology:</b> Top-Down Design Approach, Technology Trends.\n\n
<b>MOS Technology:</b> Introduction to Microelectronics and MOS Technology, Basic Electrical
Properties and Circuit Design Processes of MOS and Bi CMOS Circuits,, MOS, NMOS,
CMOS Inverters, Pass Transistor and Pass Gates, DC and Transient Characteristics.
        Overview of Fabrication Process: NMOS, PMOS, CMOS, Bi-CMOS Process.\n\n
<b>NMOS and CMOS Layout:</b> Color Plate Stick Diagram, and Design Rules.
CMOS Circuit Characteristics: Resistance and Capacitance, Rise and Fall Time, Power
Estimation. \n\n
<b>Introduction to Bi-CMOS Circuits:</b> Shifter, an ALU Sub-System, Adder, Counter,
Multipliers, Multiplexer, Data Path And Memory Structures, Buffer Circuit Design, DCVS
Logic. \n\n
<b>Design and Test-Ability:</b> Circuit Partitioning, Floor Planning and Placement, Routing,
Practical Aspects of Design Tools and Test-Ability MOS Design, Behavioral Description,
Structural Description, Physical Description and Design Verification.\n\n

    </string>

    <string name="cse_4209">
        <b>Introduction:</b> History of Computer Hardware, Software, Networking; Overview of
Technological Change; Impact of Information Technology on Some Sectors.\n\n
<b>Privacy and Personal Information:</b> Personal Privacy, Computer Technology Effect
Privacy, Moral Problems from Privacy Violation, Privacy Protection: Ethical and Legal
Basis, Technological Strategies, Implications of Database Systems.
Freedom of Expression in Cyberspace: Offensive Speech and Censorship in
Cyberspace, Pornography, Anonymity, Spam.\n\n
<b>Computer and Software Reliability</b>: Liability in Hardware and Software Failure,
Responsibility s. Liability vs. Accountability, Historical Software Risks (such as the Therac-25 Case).
Intellectual Property: Intellectual Property, Copyrights, Patents, and Trade Secrets,
Software Piracy, Software Patents, Pirated Software, Use of Licensed Software.\n\n
<b>Computer Crime:</b> History and Examples of Computer Crime; “Cracking” (“Hacking”) and
its Effects; Viruses, Worms, and Trojan Horses; Online Scams, Identity Theft; Moral
Issues Related to These Crimes.\n\n
<b>Computer and Work:</b> Impact of Employment, Work Environment, Employee Monitoring,
Health Issues.\n\n
<b>Professional Ethics and Responsibilities:</b> Ethics, Computer Ethics, Ethical Guidelines
for Computer Professionals, Examine and Discuss Professional Codes of Ethics, Conduct,
and Practice (IEEE, ACM, SE, AITP, and so forth). \n\n
    </string>

    <string name="cse_4211">
        <b>Introduction:</b> Network components, Theoretical Network, Real World Networks.
Network Architectural Design: Designing the LAN, Configuring the Network Server and
Client, Network Administration, Remote Access, Expanding the Network, Wide Area
Network Troubleshooting, Major Protocol Suites.\n\n
<b>Network Simulation:</b> Network Simulation and Optimization, Network Operations, Control
and Maintenance, Network Administration, Network Management Database and Tools,
Capacity Planning.\n\n
<b>Network Optimization:</b> Network Security and Integrity, Linear Programming and Network
Algorithms for Planning, Reliability Theory and Network Planning.\n\n
    </string>

    <string name="cse_4213">
       <b>Introduction:</b> Key Concepts of Knowledge Representation and Reasoning, Language of
First Order Logic, Syntax, Semantics Pragmatics, Expressing Knowledge, Levels of
Representation, Knowledge Acquisition and Sharing, Sharing Ontologies, Language
Ontologies, Language Patterns, Tools for Knowledge Acquisition.\n\n
<b>Resolution and Reasoning:</b> Proportional Case, Handling Variables and Qualifies,
Dealing with Intractability, Reasoning with Horn Clauses, Procedural Control of
Reasoning, Rules in Production, Description Logic, Vivid Knowledge, Beyond Vivid.\n\n
<b>Representation:</b> Object Oriented Representations, Frame Formalism, Structured
Descriptions, Meaning and Entailment, Taxonomies and Classification, Inheritance,
Networks, Strategies for Defensible Inheritance, Formal Account of Inheritance Networks.
Defaults, Uncertainty and Expressiveness: Closed World Reasoning, Circumscription,
Default Logic Limitations of Logic, Fuzzy Logic, Non-monotonic Logic, Theories and
World, Semiotics, Auto epistemic Logic, Vagueness, Uncertainty and Degrees of Belief,
Noncategorical Reasoning, Objective and Subjective Probability.\n\n
<b>Actions and Planning:</b> Explanation and Diagnosis, Syntax, Semantics of Context, First
Order Reasoning, Modal Reasoning in Context, Encapsulating Objects in Context, Agents,
Actions, Situational Calculus, Frame Problem, Complex Actions, Planning,
Strips – Planning as Reasoning – Hierarchical and Conditional Planning.\n\n
    </string>

    <string name="cse_4215">
        <b>Introduction:</b> Network Security Policies, Strategies and Guidelines; Network Security
Assessments and Matrices.\n\n
<b>Different Attacks:</b> Denial of Service (Dos) Attack, Distributed Denial of Service (Ddos)
Attack, Eavesdropping, IP Spoofing, Sybil Attack, Blackhole Attack, Grayhole Attack, Man-In-The-Middle Attack, Passwords-based Offline Attacks.
Network Security Threats and Attackers: Intruders, Malicious Software, Viruses and
Spy-Ware; Security Standards: DES, RSA, DHA, Digital Signature Algorithm (DSA), SHA,
AES; Security At Transport Layer: Secure Socket Layer (SSL) and Transport Layer
Security (TLS).\n\n
<b>Security on Network Layer:</b> Ipsec; Network Security Applications: AAA Standards, E-Mail Securities, PGP, S/MIME; PKI Smart Cards; Sandboxing; Firewalls and Proxy Server;\n\n
<b>Security for Wireless Network Protocols:</b> WEP, WPA, TKIP, EAP, LEAP; Security
Protocols for Ad-Hoc Network; Security Protocols for Sensor Network; Security for
Communication Protocols; Security for Operating System and Mobile Agents; Security for
E-Commerce; Security for LAN and WAN; Switching and Routing Security; other State-Of-The-Art Related Topics.\n\n
    </string>

    <string name="cse_4217">
        <b>Introduction to Decision Support System:</b> DSS Characteristics, Applications of
Decision Support Systems, Capabilities of Decision Support Systems, Components of
Decision Support Systems, Benefits of using DSS Systems.\n\n
<b>Making Decisions in the Decision Support Systems Environment:</b> Activities in the
Decision Support Systems Environment, the Decision Making Process, Information Use
for Strategic Management, Making Decisions in the Decision Support Systems.\n\n
        <b>Environment:</b> Strategic Analysis for the Organization, Types of Problems in the Decision
Making Process.\n\n
<b>Developing Decision Support System:</b> Approaches to DSS Development, DSS
Software Tools, DSS Hardware and Operating System Platforms, Building and
Implementing Decision Support Systems. Decision Support Systems in Detail: Types of
Decision Support Systems, DSS Models, Data Mining, Group Decision, Support Systems,
Executive Information Systems (EIS). Artificial Intelligence and Expert Systems, Systems
Integration and the Future of DSS: Brainstorming.\n\n
    </string>

    <string name="cse_4219">
        <b>introduction:</b> Introduction to Computer Vision, Case Study-Face Recognition, Linear
Algebra/Probability Review. \n\n
<b>Image Structure:</b> Linear Filters, Finding Lines-From Detection to Model Fitting, Clustering
and Segmentation.\n\n
<b>Camera Models:</b> Camera Models, Camera Calibration, Epipolar Geometry, Stereo and
Multi-view Reconstruction.\n\n
<b>Recognition (Building blocks):</b> Detectors and Descriptors, SIFT and Single Object
Recognition, Optical Flow and Tracking.\n\n
<b>Recognition (Objects, Scenes, and Activities):</b> Introduction to Object Recognition and
Bag-of-Words Models, Object Classification and Detection- A Part-based Generative
Model (Constellation Model), Object Classification and Detection: A Part-Based
Discriminative Model (Latent SVM), Human Motion Recognition.\n\n
        <b>Computer Vision:</b> State-of-the-art and the Future.\n\n
    </string>

    <string name="cse_4221">
     <b>Data Mining and Applications:</b> Relational Databases, Data Warehouses, Transactional
Databases, Advanced Data and Information Systems, Characterization and
Discrimination, Mining Frequent Patterns, Associations, and Correlations, Classification
and Prediction, Cluster Analysis, Outlier Analysis, Evolution Analysis.\n\n
<b>Data Preprocessing:</b> Descriptive Data Summarization, Data Cleaning, Data Integration
and Transformation, Data Reduction, Data Discretization and Concept Hierarchy
Generation.\n\n
<b>Classification, Clustering and Prediction:</b> Classification by Decision Tree Induction,
Bayesian Classification, Rule-Based Classification, Classification by Backpropagation,
Support Vector Machines, Clustering by Partitioning/ Hierarchical/ Density-based/ Grid-based/ Model-based Methods, Clustering High-Dimensional Data, Outlier Analysis,
Prediction, Linear Regression, Nonlinear Regression, Other Regression-Based Methods
of Prediction, Evaluating the Accuracy and Error Measures of a Classifier or Predictor.\n\n
<b>Web Mining:</b> Anatomy of a Search Engine, Crawling the Web, Web Graph Analysis,
Extracting Structured Data from the Web, Classification and Vertical Search, Web Log
Analysis.\n\n
<b>Advanced Analysis:</b> Mining Stream, Time-Series, and Sequence Data, Graph Mining,
Social Network Analysis, and Multirelational data Mining, Mining Object, Spatial,
Multimedia, and Text Data.\n\n
 </string>

</resources>